this video is about the coalitional game
这个视频是关于联盟游戏的
theory solution concept called the core
理论解决方案概念称为核心
recall that the Shapley value told us
记得夏普利价值告诉我们
about how to divide the coalition's
关于如何划分联盟的
value fairly among all of its members in
公平地在其所有成员中重视
this video we instead want to think
这个视频我们反而想
about whether the agents would be
关于代理商是否会
willing to form the grand coalition as
愿意组成大联盟
compared to forming smaller coalition's
与组建较小的联盟相比
that might give all of their members
可能会给所有成员
greater value than they're able to
比他们能够提供的更大的价值
achieve in the grand coalition let's
在大联盟中实现，让我们
begin by looking at an example which
首先看一个例子
we're going to call the voting game
我们要叫投票游戏
we're going to think about a parliament
我们要考虑一个议会
that consists of four political parties
由四个政党组成
which we'll call a b c and d each of
我们将其分别称为abc和d
these parties have different numbers of
这些政党有不同数量的
seats in the parliament 45 seats 25 15
议会席位45席位25 15
and 15 respectively the parties have to
和15个当事方分别
vote to decide whether to pass a
投票决定是否通过
spending bill of a hundred million
一亿支出
dollars and also to decide amongst
美元，并决定
themselves how to divide that spending
自己如何分配支出
between the parties it's necessary to
双方之间有必要
get a majority which is to say 51 votes
获得多数票，即51票
in order to pass any legislation and of
为了通过任何法律和
course if the bill doesn't pass then
当然如果账单没有通过的话
there'll be no money for any of the
没有任何钱
parties to spend let's begin by thinking
花钱的聚会让我们从思考开始
about the Shapley values in this case
关于这种情况下的Shapley值
I'll tell you what the answer is in a
我会告诉你答案是什么
second but you may want to pause the
第二，但您可能要暂停
video here and work out for yourself
视频在这里，自己动手做
what the Shapley values are in this
Shapley值是什么
situation so these are the Shapley
情况就是这些Shapley
values here I won't show you how we did
这里的值我不会告诉你我们如何做
the calculation notice in particular
特别是计算通知
that even though B and C and D have
即使B和C和D有
different numbers of votes they end up
他们最终获得不同数量的选票
getting the same value in the Shapley
在Shapley中获得相同的值
value the question that I want to focus
重视我要关注的问题
on today is whether any sub coalition
今天是否有任何子联盟
can gain by defecting from the grand
可以从盛大的叛逃中获利
coalition again I'll invite you to pause
再次联盟，我邀请你暂停
and think about that before I give you
在我给你之前先想一想
the answer
答案
so the answer is that a sub coalition
所以答案是一个子联盟
can gain in particular a and B together
可以一起获得a和B
could form a sub coalition which would
可以组成一个子联盟
do better than the grand coalition and
比大联盟做得更好
being paid according to the Shapley
根据夏普利支付
values so a and B by themselves have
因此a和B本身具有的值
enough votes to pass the legislation
足够的票数通过立法
without the help of C and D and if they
没有C和D的帮助，如果他们
were to divide the hundred million
要分亿
amongst themselves for example 75 25
例如75 25
then they would each get more than they
那么他们每个人都会得到比他们更多的收益
got under the Shapley value division and
隶属于Shapley价值部门
they would still pass the legislation so
他们仍然会通过立法，所以
this goes to show that while the Shapley
这表明，沙普利
values may be fair they don't
价值观可能公平，但不公平
necessarily give the right incentives to
必然会给
all of the different parties to want to
所有各方想要
actually join the grand coalition and so
实际上加入了大联盟等等
instead we should look for different
相反，我们应该寻找不同的
ways that the parties could divide the
各方可以分割的方式
payments so that they would be willing
付款，以便他们愿意
to form the grand coalition so that's
组成大联盟，所以
the question that we're going to think
我们要思考的问题
about in this video
关于这部影片
under what payment divisions would the
在什么付款部门下
agents be willing to form the grand
代理商愿意组建宏伟
coalition and the answer as we'll see is
联盟，我们将看到的答案是
that they would be willing to do so if
他们愿意这样做，如果
the payment profile belongs to a set
付款资料属于一组
which we'll call the core here's how we
我们将其称为核心的是我们的方式
define the core so we're going to think
定义核心，以便我们思考
about a given payment vector that's
关于给定的支付向量
going to be an assignment of a certain
将是某人的任务
amount of value to each of the different
每个不同的价值
members of the coalition and we're going
联盟成员，我们要去
to say that the core that this payment
要说的是核心，这笔付款
vector is in the core of a coalitional
向量是联盟的核心
game if and only if the following
当且仅当以下情况时
condition is true for every coalition
每个联盟的条件都成立
that could form and which is a subset or
可能形成，并且是子集或
equal to the grand coalition so every
等于大联盟，所以每一个
subset of the grand coalition it's the
大联盟的子集是
case that for all agents in that subset
对于该子集中的所有代理
and if we sum across all of the agents
如果我们汇总所有代理商
in that subset excuse me the amount of
在那个子集中，请问
payoff that the payoff vector says that
收益向量表示
we give to each of those agents I in the
我们给我中的每个代理商
subset that sum
总和的子集
is at least as much as the value that
至少与
the agents would have gotten as a
特工们会成为
coalition if they had deviated and
如果他们偏离了联盟，
instead formed that subset s so kind of
而是形成了这样的子集
intuitively what we're guaranteeing here
直觉上我们在这里保证
is that the sum of the payoffs to all of
是所有的收益的总和
the agents in any sub coalition is at
任何子联盟中的特工都在
least as much as they could earn if they
如果他们至少赚了多少钱
actually did go off and formed that sub
实际上确实消失并形成了那个子
coalition and you can see in the voting
联盟，你可以在投票中看到
game that's what we saw wasn't achieved
我们看到的游戏没有实现
that the amount that we were paying a
我们支付的金额是
and B under the Shapley value payments
Shapley价值支付项下的B
wasn't as much as they could have gone
没有他们本应走的那么多
off and gone gotten on their own so if
离开并自行离开，所以如果
there doesn't exist any sub coalition
没有任何子联盟
where the agents could have gotten more
代理商可以得到更多的地方
on their own then our pay effector is in
靠我们自己的薪酬影响者
the core and intuitively this is like
核心，直觉上这就像
Nash equilibrium because what we're
纳什均衡，因为我们
saying is the agents don't have any
说的是代理商没有
profitable deviations it isn't the case
实际情况并非如此
that any sub coalition could deviate
任何子联盟都可能会偏离
away from the grand coalition and end up
离开大联盟并结束
with higher payments for themselves the
自己支付更高的
way it's different from Nash equilibrium
不同于纳什均衡的方式
is we're thinking about groups of agents
我们在考虑代理商群体吗
jointly deviating so in a sense it's a
共同偏离，从某种意义上说
stronger notion than a Nash equilibrium
比纳什均衡更强的概念
we don't think only about unilateral
我们不仅考虑单方面
deviations here so anytime a solution
出现偏差，因此随时可以解决
concept is introduced to you there are
概念介绍给你有
two questions that you should wonder
您应该怀疑的两个问题
about the first is whether the solution
关于第一个是解决方案
concept always returns something
概念总是返回一些东西
analogously remember pure strategy Nash
类似地记得纯策略纳什
equilibrium doesn't always exist mixed
平衡并不总是存在
strategy equilibrium does always exist
战略均衡始终存在
so we might wonder is the core always
所以我们可能想知道核心始终是
non-empty does it always suggest at
非空的总是建议
least one payment profile to us secondly
第二个给我们至少一个付款资料
we might wonder is the core always
我们可能想知道核心始终是
unique when it does return something to
当它确实返回某些东西时是唯一的
us does it always return one thing does
我们做它总是返回一件事
it make a sharp recommendation or might
它提出了一个尖锐的建议，或者可能
it return multiple things well first of
它首先会很好地返回多个事物
all is the core always non-empty the
一切都是核心，永远是非空的
answer here unfortunately is no so there
不幸的是，这里没有答案
are some games in which there aren't any
有些游戏没有
stable payments that can be allocated to
可以分配给的稳定付款
the agents and we can see this already
代理商，我们已经可以看到
in the voting game so
在投票游戏中
the set of minimal coalition's that are
最小联盟的集合是
able to pass the legislation are a b a c
能够通过立法的是算盘
a d and b c d all of these subsets of
ad和bcd的所有这些子集
the agents have enough votes to pass the
代理商有足够的票数可以通过
legislation now we can just looking at
立法现在我们可以看看
these sets reason that there isn't any
这些设置的原因是没有任何
way of dividing the payments that would
分割付款方式
be stable for all sub coalition's in
对所有子联盟的稳定
particular we can see that if the sum of
特别是我们可以看到，如果
the payoffs to the parties in b c and d
BC和d中各方的收益
ends up being less than 100 then this
最终小于100则这个
set of agents has reason to deviate and
一组代理人有偏离的理由
form this coalition where they can then
组建这个联盟，然后他们可以
divide the full hundred million amongst
将整亿分给
themselves
他们自己
however if b c and d get the entire
但是，如果bc和d得到整个
payoff of a hundred million then a can
一亿的回报，然后一罐
form a coalition with anyone of b c or d
与BC或D的任何人结盟
which would be sufficient and it could
这将是足够的，并且可以
do this with whichever of the of b c and
使用BC和
d is getting paid the least under
d的薪水最低
whatever payment profile were assuming
假设的付款方式是什么
is adequate for for b c and d and thus
对于bc和d是足够的，因此
we can see that there's always some sub
我们可以看到总是有一些子
coalition that could profitably deviate
可能有利可图的偏离联盟
from any payment profile that we
从我们的任何付款资料中
proposed and that means that the core is
建议，这意味着核心是
empty for this game the second thing we
为这个游戏清空第二件事
might wonder is in cases where the core
可能会怀疑是在核心
is not empty is it unique and again here
不是空的，它是唯一的，还是在这里
the news is bad because no the core is
这消息不好，因为没有核心
not always unique so now let's consider
并不总是唯一的，所以现在让我们考虑
changing the voting game so that we
更改投票游戏，以便我们
require an 80 percent majority instead
需要80％的多数
of a 51% majority it's now the case that
在51％的多数中，情况就是这样
the winning coalition's are these two
获胜的联盟是这两个
coalition's these are the only
这些是唯一的
coalition's that are able to obtain 80%
能够获得80％的联盟
majorities are the only minimal
多数是唯一的最低要求
coalition's and it's now the case that a
联盟，现在情况是
and B are required in all winning
所有获胜都需要B和B
coalition's and this means that any
联盟的，这意味着任何
complete distribution of the hundred
百分百的完整分配
million between just a and B is going to
仅在A和B之间的百万
belong to the Corps because there's no
属于兵团，因为没有
way that C and
C和
even if they're not paid anything can go
即使他们没有得到任何报酬也可以
off and form some different coalition
并组成一些不同的联盟
that would pay them more and so the the
那会给他们更多的报酬，所以
grand coalition is stable as long as a
大联盟只要稳定
and B get paid everything now let me
和B现在得到了所有的报酬让我
give you a few more definitions so I can
给您更多定义，以便我可以
say some more positive things about the
说一些更积极的事情
Corps first let me define a simple game
军团首先让我定义一个简单的游戏
I'll say that a game is simple if it's
我会说一个简单的游戏
the case that for all coalition's the
对于所有联盟来说
value of the Coalition is either 0 or 1
联盟的值为0或1
and notice that our voting game is a
并注意我们的投票游戏是
simple game and the reason is that we
简单的游戏，原因是我们
either produce a hundred million dollars
要么产生一亿美元
or 0 depending on whether we get a
或0取决于我们是否得到
majority or not and so we can scale
是否多数，所以我们可以扩展
those payoffs where one is 100 million
一亿的回报
dollars and 0 is 0 and we can then
美元，0是0，然后我们可以
encode this as a simple game my second
第二，将其编码为一个简单的游戏
definition is of a veto player and I'll
定义是否决权，我将
say that a player I has a veto if the
说如果我拥有否决权，
value of all coalition's that don't
所有联盟的价值
involve AI is 0 so in other words the
涉及AI为0，也就是说
participation of AI in a coalition is
AI参与联盟是
necessary if the Coalition is going to
如果联盟要
produce any value at all
根本没有任何价值
putting these two things together it's
将这两件事放在一起
possible to show that in a simple game
可以在一个简单的游戏中证明这一点
the core is empty exactly when there is
核心在存在时恰好是空的
no veto player and that's precisely what
没有否决权，这正是
we saw in our voting game example
我们在投票游戏示例中看到了
already we had no veto player in the
我们已经没有否决权
case where we needed a 51% majority
我们需要51％多数的情况
because there was a coalition that
因为有一个联盟
didn't involve a on the other hand and
另一方面不涉及
the core was empty in that case on the
在那种情况下，核心是空的
other hand if there are veto players the
另一方面，如果有否决权
core consists of all of those payoff
核心包括所有这些收益
vectors where the non veto players get 0
非否决玩家得到0的向量
and the payoff is divided among the veto
收益在否决权之间分配
players and again we saw that in our
玩家，我们再次在我们身上看到了
voting game example here where we had
我们在这里投票游戏的例子
the 80% majority required where a and B
a和B要求80％的多数
were both veto players
都是否决权参与者
I want to say one more positive thing
我想说一件事
about the core and to do that I'm going
关于核心，要做到这一点
to illustrate another coalitional game
来说明另一个联盟游戏
example so this is called the airport
这样的例子叫做机场
game in this example there are several
这个例子中的游戏有几个
different cities in the same
同一城市中的不同城市
geographical area that need access to
需要访问的地理区域
airports and the different cities are
机场和不同的城市是
different sizes and so they need to be
不同的尺寸，所以它们需要
able to accommodate different sized
能够容纳不同尺寸
airplanes they have to decide between
他们必须决定之间的飞机
each building their own Airport or
每个人都建立自己的机场或
building a Regional Airport and sharing
建立区域机场并共享
the cost of building the Regional
建设区域的成本
Airport amongst all the cities if they
所有城市中的机场
build the Regional Airport its cost is
建立区域机场，其成本是
going to depend on the largest plane
要依靠最大的飞机
that has to be accommodated so whichever
无论如何都要容纳
city in the coalition that builds a
建立联盟的城市
regional airport needs the biggest
支线机场需求最大
aircraft is going to set the size of the
飞机将要设置的大小
airport for everybody otherwise everyone
每个人的机场，否则每个人
just builds their own Airport so we'll
只是建立自己的机场，所以我们将
model this as a coalitional game as
将此模型建模为联盟游戏
follows n is of course the set of cities
跟随n当然是城市的集合
and the value of each coalition is
每个联盟的价值是
basically the amount of work that was
基本上是
avoided as compared to having all of the
与拥有所有
airports built individually for each
每个机场分别建造
city so more specifically the value of a
城市，更具体地说，一个城市的价值
coalition is the sum of the cost of
联盟是成本的总和
building runways for every city and s
为每个城市和城市建造跑道
minus the cost of the biggest runway
减去最大跑道的成本
which is the one that actually has to be
这实际上是必须的
built for the Regional Airport
为地区机场而建
well I'll define a convex game as
好吧，我将凸游戏定义为
follows a game is convex if for all
如果所有
coalition's that are strict subsets of n
是n的严格子集的联盟
the value of the union of those subsets
这些子集的并集值
of those two different coalition's is at
这两个不同联盟中的一个
least as big as the value that the first
至少与第一个价值一样大
can achieve by itself plus the amount
可以自己实现加上数量
the second could achieve by itself minus
第二个可以自己实现
the amount that the coalition in common
联盟的共同点
between these two can achieve for itself
这两个之间可以自己实现
so notice that we already talked about
所以请注意，我们已经讨论过
super a nativity this is a stronger
超级耶稣降生这是一个更强大
assumption because super additive 'ti
假设是因为超级添加剂
assumed that SMT had an empty
假设SMT空着
intersection whereas here we're allowing
相交而我们在这里允许
them to have an intersection and were
他们有一个十字路口，
considered we're just subtracting the
认为我们只是减去
value of its intersection so so this
相交的值，所以这样
speaks about also cases in which SMT do
还谈到了SMT的情况
have one or more agents in common
有一个或多个共同的代理
nevertheless convex games are relatively
但是凸游戏相对
common and the airport game is an
常见的机场游戏是
example of a contacts game so the reason
接触游戏的例子，原因
I mentioned convex games is to say some
我提到凸游戏是说一些
nice things about the core and here are
关于核心的好东西是
two kind of positive theorems about the
关于的两种正定理
core first of all in the case of convex
首先是凸的情况下的核心
games the core always is non-empty so
游戏的核心总是非空的，所以
there's always at least some way of
总是至少有某种方式
dividing payments between all of the
在所有
agents to support the grand coalition
代理商支持大联盟
and in a way where no subset of the
并且以某种方式
agents would be willing to deviate in
代理商会愿意偏离
order to benefit themselves secondly
其次使自己受益
even better the Shapley value is in the
更好的是Shapley的价值在于
core for convex games and so that means
凸游戏的核心，这意味着
that for these particular games dividing
对于这些特定的游戏划分
the the value of the grand coalition in
大联盟的价值
a way that is stable and dividing the
一种稳定并划分
value of the grand coalition in a way
大联盟的价值在某种程度上
that is fair are not goals that are at
公平不是目标
odds with each other
彼此的赔率
so in these games it's possible to do
因此在这些游戏中可以
both
都